const statements = [
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of the 'if' statement in JavaScript?",
    options: ["To declare a new variable", "To create a loop", "To execute a block of code conditionally", "To define a function"],
    correctAnswer: "To execute a block of code conditionally",
  },
  {
    question: "Which keyword is used to exit a loop prematurely in JavaScript?",
    options: ["break", "continue", "return", "exit"],
    correctAnswer: "break",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of the 'switch' statement in JavaScript?",
    options: ["To declare variables", "To create a loop", "To handle multiple conditions in a compact way", "To define a function"],
    correctAnswer: "To handle multiple conditions in a compact way",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the role of the 'else' statement in an 'if-else' block?",
    options: ["To execute the code inside the 'if' block", "To execute the code inside the 'else' block", "To handle errors", "To define a function"],
    correctAnswer: "To execute the code inside the 'else' block",
  },
  {
    question: "Which statement is used to terminate the execution of a function in JavaScript?",
    options: ["break", "return", "exit", "terminate"],
    correctAnswer: "return",
  },
  {
    question: "What does the 'throw' statement do in JavaScript?",
    options: ["Creates a new variable", "Generates a random number", "Throws an exception", "Defines a function"],
    correctAnswer: "Throws an exception",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of the 'try...catch' statement in JavaScript?",
    options: ["To declare variables", "To handle errors gracefully", "To create a loop", "To define a function"],
    correctAnswer: "To handle errors gracefully",
  },
  {
    question: "Which statement is used to iterate over the elements of an array in JavaScript?",
    options: ["for", "while", "do-while", "foreach"],
    correctAnswer: "for",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of the 'continue' statement in JavaScript?",
    options: [
      "To terminate the program",
      "To skip the current iteration of a loop",
      "To jump to a specific line of code",
      "To resume execution after an error",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "To skip the current iteration of a loop",
  },
  {
    question: "Which statement is used to define a block of code that will be executed repeatedly in JavaScript?",
    options: ["if", "switch", "for", "try"],
    correctAnswer: "for",
  },
];
module.exports = statements;
